[Music]
hey everybody and welcome to my channel
today I wanted to show you how to
crochet these super simple and textured
yet elegant flowers now if this is your
first visit to my channel it would be
amazing if you just took a moment take
that subscribe button and the bail
notification so you don't miss out on
any of my future videos look for this
petal technique I saw this demonstrated
on a beautiful video where they're made
in a big long round and rolled up into a
rose now I will link to that video in
the description box below so don't
forget to take a moment to just expand
the box down there by clicking the
little arrow so you can watch that video
now I believe it is in Spanish but you
can follow along just by watching now
the Rose was absolutely stunning and I
made one but I found that it was taking
just fractionally a bit too long for my
liking because I am an impatient kind of
girl so I wanted to take the absolutely
beautiful petal technique and apply it
to something a bit quicker a bit simpler
and a bit faster hence this little
flower has been born but full credit to
that video which I've linked to below
for showing me this really pretty
technique for the petals themselves
alright let's jump straight into how we
make these flowers now I'm going to be
using a 4 millimeter crochet hook and
some cotton yarn from mine just normal
double knit but these will work for any
yarn and any corresponding hook size now
with my yellow I'm going to start by
making a magic ring now if you don't
know how to make magic ring I do have a
video on how to do just that which I've
linked to in the description box below
or a little I will have popped up over
here now from the magic ring you're
going to chain one quite loosely it's
like a two loose chain which does not
count as a stitch then into the magic
ring you're going to place 12 double
crochet stitches
so once you have your 12 double crochet
you can go ahead and close your magic
ring but don't pull it all the way
closed just yet because you don't want
to lose the top of this first double
crochet and you want to go ahead and
slip stitch to the top of that first
double crochet ignoring the chain one
cut your yarn leaving a decent long
length for weaving in afterwards
then you can go ahead and pull that yarn
through and finish closing the magic
ring at the back pull it nice and tight
then weave in your end of the yellow
you
don't forget to also weave in the end or
your Magic Circle
you
now we're going to do the petals so put
your hook underneath that double crochet
next to where you slip stitched and
bring in your petal color
pop a slip knot on your hook and bring
that loop to the front of your work
now to begin your first petal chain 5
and working back into this exact same
stitch that you've just joined your yarn
- we're going to be doing trebles
american term trebles
which is a yarn over twice see yuan over
twice go into that stitch go back
through you'll have four loops on your
hook yarn over pull through two yarn
over pull through two and then stop so
you want to leave that first treble and
all the remaining treble stitches
unfinished now we want seven of these
half finished treble stitches in total
all working into this same stitch things
are going to get pretty tight but bear
with it so yarn over twice go back into
the same stitch and yarn over pull
through two yarn over pull through two
and stop at that point so seven of those
in total we've done two I need 5 more
you
all right once you have your seven part
finished
trebles hanging from your hook you got
your chain five and your seven you'll
have one two three four five six seven
eight loops on your hook now we're going
to work them off a Tunisian crochet
style so you're going to yarn over and
pull through the first loop then for the
remaining loops yarn over pull through
two yarn over pull through two keep
doing that until you only have one loop
remaining on your hook
then we're going to skip this chain five
and we're going to be working in between
your first trebles so in here so skip
here put your hook straight in at the
top and do a single crochet single
crochet in between the next two triples
and single crochet in between the next
so you'll have three single crochets
chain two and place a single crochet
back into that same space then we're
going to work three more single crochets
in between your stitches
chain five and then slip stitch back
into this exact same space where all
those stitches have been placed it's
pretty tight in there but that causes
these petals to curve now you're going
to skip the next stitch which is pretty
much crushed and hiding so you may need
to pull things around skip this stitch
here and put a slip stitch into the next
so skip one slip stitch into the next
then we're going to repeat the petals
it's a chain five
then we're going to do seven
half-finished rebels into this same
stitch
once you have your seven half-finished
treble stitches and your eight loops on
your hook yarn over pull through one
loop and then yarn over pull through two
ignore your chain five and work in
between the treble stitches three single
crochet
chained to place a single crochet back
into that same space so you have single
crochet chain two single crochet and
then three more single crochet in
between your travels
chain 5
and slip stitch back into that same
stitch skip a stitch slip stitch into
the next and repeat this petal four more
times around so petal skip a stitch
petal skip a stitch petal skip a stitch
keep going
and you'll end up with six petals
when you've done your last petal cut
your yarn leaving a decent length to
weave in pull that yarn through and
you'll see that all your petals have got
one curled side and one flatter side and
you want to place the curled sides
behind the petals if they'll stay there
but that's the direction you want your
flower to be going in its the curled
sides are behind then grab your needle
and weave in this end now for this final
petal I like to attach it to this first
one just for security but it's totally
up to you
you
and that's all there is to it so these
flowers get really quick once you get
used to this sort of half normal crochet
half Tunisian crochet style of working
if you want your flowers to truly stick
up you could of course stitch the petals
together to force them in that shape but
I quite like the flat fact that you can
flatten them out if you want to or you
can have them more curved depending on
the look you want to go for so I hope
you enjoyed this tutorial as I said I
have linked to the video below which
shows how you make a beautiful rose
using this petal technique with just a
few more stitches in between and it
would be amazing if you haven't already
if you hit that subscribe button or
perhaps share this video with someone
who you think may also enjoy making
these really pretty little 3d textured
simple flowers so until next time happy
crocheting bowi
[Music]